John Tillman Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
John Tillman Collection
1927-1936
1957-1966
NPkMC-225-022
5 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
John Tillman
John Tillman was a long-time reporter, anchor and announcer for WB 11 WPIX News in New York from its start-up in 1948 until 1967. This collection contains records of news reports, original 16mm film cores, and quarter inch audio news reels, all pertaining to the reporting and news casting of John Tillman for WPIX New York through the years of 1948 to 1967.
Collection Overview
This collection contains records of news reports, original 16mm film cores, and quarter inch audio news reels, all pertaining to the reporting and news casting of John Tillman for WPIX New York through the years of 1948 to 1967. The subject matter contained in the film interviews is of metropolitan New York, including footage of former NYC Mayor John Lindsay. Also contained in this collection, aside from the WPIX news materials is record industry information collected by Tillman from the 1920s and 1930s.
Acquisitions Informantion
John Tillman donated this collection to Marist College in 1980.
Biographical Note
John Tillman of Rivercross, Roosevelt Island, New York was a long-time reporter, anchor and announcer for WB 11 WPIX News in New York from its start-up in 1948 until 1967. Prior to working in television news he had been a radio announcer and after WPIX he was a spokesperson for The Port Authority of New York and New Jersey in 1977. Reports and interviews by John Tillman were part of a segment interchangeably called ‘On-The-Spot/On-the-Scene Reports’ from 1957-1965. During his time at WPIX Tillman’s reports covered subjects such as, the Metropolitan New York area and issues of National and International significance. His interview subjects were from the fields of politics, sports and entertainment. WPIX, channel 11’s newscasts cover the tri-state New York metropolitan area. In 2006, the WB and UPN networks merged into The CW Television Network and the WPIX newscast became CW11 News, in 2008 it became PIX News. As of 2022, it is now WPIX news.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Collection is arranged into four series: 1) Time Tables of Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, 2) Original 16mm film (cores): WPIX, 3) Quarter Inch Audio News Reels, and 4) Record Industry Information
- 1. Time Tables of Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, 1957-1965; 1; Folders: 1 - 68 Boxes: 1 - 2
  - Details of the contribution of The John Tillman Collection to Marist College and tape inventory (2 copies), 1986 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Interview subjects, July 1, 1957- December 31, 1957 (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, May 1959 (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, June 1959 (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, July 1959 (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, August 1959 (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, September 1959 (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, October 1959 (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, November 1959 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, December 1959 (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, January 1960 (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, February 1960 (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, March 1960 (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Coverage’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, April 1960 (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, May 1960 (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, June 1960 (Folder 16, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, July 1960 (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, August 1960 (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, September 1960 (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, October 1960 (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, November 1960 (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, December 1960 (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, January 1961 (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, February 1961 (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot/ On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, March 1961 (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, April 1961 (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, May 1961 (Folder 27, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, June 1961 (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, August 1961 (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene News Reporting’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, September 1961 (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, October 1961 (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, November 1961 (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, December 1961 (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, January 1962 (Folder 34, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, February 1962 (Folder 35, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, March 1962 (Folder 36, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, April 1962 (Folder 37, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, May 1962 (Folder 38, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, June 1962 (Folder 39, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, July 1962 (Folder 40, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, September 1962 (Folder 41, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, October 1962 (Folder 42, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, November 1962 (Folder 43, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, December 1962 (Folder 44, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, January 1963 (Folder 45, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, February 1963 (Folder 46, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, March 1963 (Folder 47, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Spot Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, April 1963 (Folder 48, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, May 1963 (Folder 49, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, June 1963 (Folder 50, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, July 1963 (Folder 51, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, August 1963 (Folder 52, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, September 1963 (Folder 53, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, October 1963 (Folder 54, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, November 1963 (Folder 55, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, December 1963 (Folder 56, Box 1)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, January 1965 (Folder 57, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, February 1965 (Folder 58, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, March 1965 (Folder 59, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, April 1965 (Folder 60, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, May 1965 (Folder 61, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, June 1965 (Folder 62, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, July 1965 (Folder 63, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, August 1965 (Folder 64, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, September 1965 (Folder 65, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, October 1965 (Folder 66, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, November 1965 (Folder 67, Box 2)
  - ‘On-The-Scene Reports’- Reports and Interviews by John Tillman, December 1965 (Folder 68, Box 2)
- 2. Original 16mm film (cores): WPIX, 2; Folders: 1 - 20 Box: 3
  - Robert Moses at Triboro 30th Anniversary, undated (Folder 1, Box 3)
  - Robert Moses at dedication Lehman 200, undated (Folder 2, Box 3)
  - Robert Moses on New Bruckner Expressway, undated (Folder 3, Box 3)
  - Robert Moses at NY World’s Fair with Indian Chief, undated (Folder 4, Box 3)
  - Fire Island Highway Controversy; Interviews with residents; hearing, Robert Moses, undated (Folder 5, Box 3)
  - Protestors at City Hall against Robert Moses, Breezy Pt. Development, undated (Folder 6, Box 3)
  - Politician interview re: opposition to Breezy Pt. development, undated (Folder 7, Box 3)
  - Rent control protestors, City Hall, undated (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Mayor John Lindsay on housing renewal, undated (Folder 9, Box 3)
  - Mayor John Lindsay on Transit Strike, undated (Folder 10, Box 3)
  - Paul Screvane on mayor’s power, undated (Folder 11, Box 3)
  - Paul Screvane on L.I.E., undated (Folder 12, Box 3)
  - Boat trip around NYC; traffic commissioner Barnes Interview, undated (Folder 13, Box 3)
  - Bill Haddad, undated (Folder 14, Box 3)
  - Bill Haddad on defective cars, undated (Folder 15, Box 3)
  - Paley Park, undated (Folder 16, Box 3)
  - Paley Park Interview, undated (Folder 17, Box 3)
  - Pushcarts Bleeker Street, undated (Folder 18, Box 3)
  - Archival R2 Head, undated (Folder 19, Box 3)
  - ? sd. neg., undated (Folder 20, Box 3)
- 3. Quarter Inch Audio News Reels, 3; Folders: 1 - 30 Boxes: 4 - 5
  - Reel-to-Reel (101-105), undated (Folder 1, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (1069-1075, 182), undated (Folder 2, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (896-904, 910), undated (Folder 3, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (686-695), undated (Folder 4, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (251-260), undated (Folder 5, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (363-370), undated (Folder 6, Box 4)
  - Reel-to Reel (371-378), undated (Folder 7, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (662-666, 668-670, 673-675), undated (Folder 8, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (106-110), undated (Folder 9, Box 4)
  - Information transcribed from the Reel-to-Reel: 1. R NY 1. Around NY 2. Book World 2. Thanksgiving 3. WRUL- Earl Nightingale Promo’s 4. 8/4/64 Vietnam 5. 3/15/66 From the Capital 6. 3/28/65 Voices in the Headline 7. 1/16/66 Voices in the Headline 8. 8/12- 10/63 9. 4/13-5/15/ 62 10. #795 2/13/64 United Kingdom 11. #794 10/18/63 United Kingdom, 1962-1966 (Folder 10, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (387-399), undated (Folder 11, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (751-759), undated (Folder 12, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (450, 651-655, 657-661), undated (Folder 13, Box 4)
  - Information transcribed from the Reel-to-Reel: 1. Actualities 10/6-10/14/63 2. Voices in the headline 4/24/66 3. Issues and Answers 5/15/66 4. Music 5. 1966 Mormon PT 1 6. 12/8/66 Romney- Grand Ballroom WA, 71st Annual Congress 7. Great Moments- 13 Days of valor (Hungary) 8. 8/28/63 Washington, 1963-1966 (Folder 14, Box 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel (696-697, 761, 662, 763-764, 767-768, 771-772), undated (Folder 15, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (379-386), undated (Folder 16, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (265, 267, 355-362), undated (Folder 17, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (676-679, 681-685), undated (Folder 18, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (700, 772-780), undated (Folder 19, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (781-793), undated (Folder 20, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (797-805, 698-699), undated (Folder 21, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (120-122, 81, 83-85, 91) 11/23/63- Spanish Man from Deuborn #3, 1963 (Folder 22, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (69, 70, 64, 66), undated (Folder 23, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (58-60, 62), undated (Folder 24, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (1061-1068), undated (Folder 25, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (114, 111), undated (Folder 26, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (115-118), undated (Folder 27, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (92-98, 100, 119-120), undated (Folder 28, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (1076-1083, 184), undated (Folder 29, Box 5)
  - Reel-to-Reel (112, 999, 998, 997, 996) MacArthur Memorial NYC 4/7/64 Selichot Service #56, 1964 (Folder 30, Box 5)
- 4. Record Industry Information, 4; Folders: 1 - 11 Box: 6
  - 78’s: 154 Labels, undated (Folder 1, Box 6)
  - Victor Record Catalog, 1927 (Folder 2, Box 6)
  - List of new Victor Records, February 1, 1926 (Folder 3, Box 6)
  - List of new Playtime Records, March 11, 1935 (Folder 4, Box 6)
  - List of new Perfect 25 Records, March 1936 (Folder 5, Box 6)
  - List of new Brunswick Longer Playing Records, undated (Folder 6, Box 6)
  - List of new Domino Records: November, undated (Folder 7, Box 6)
  - Top Hit Club of America record club order form, undated (Folder 8, Box 6)
  - A Little Golden Record: Rock Candy Mountain; the Blue-Tail Fly record sleeve, undated (Folder 9, Box 6)
  - Double Door Discabinets Catalog, undated (Folder 10, Box 6)
  - Notice: Help Save the Youth of America, undated (Folder 11, Box 6)